<wd:Report_Entry>
<wd:LastUpdated>2019-10-25T08:14:10.329-07:00</wd:LastUpdated>
<wd:JobCategory>Housing Management</wd:JobCategory>  -- This is what we use to classify the job into a category
<wd:JobType>Permanent</wd:JobType>
<wd:PayTextForAdvert>Annual salary: up to £60,000.00</wd:PayTextForAdvert> -- This is the field that I use to build the advert text, you may want to use this, or I've also included enough fields below to determine salary/hourly and the rate if you want to use the component parts
<wd:IsSalary>1</wd:IsSalary>
<wd:IsHourly>0</wd:IsHourly>
<wd:PayAmount>60000</wd:PayAmount> -- This will be populated with the (estimated) annual amount even if the role is hourly paid
<wd:HourlyAmount>0</wd:HourlyAmount>
<wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationID>LOCATION-3-642</wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationID>
<wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationName>Darlington</wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationName>  -- Each job posting has a primary job posting location ie the main location, there are additional locations further down
<wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationHierarchy>Yorkshire &amp; Humber</wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationHierarchy>  -- This is what we use to classify the locations into regions
<wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationAddressOne>Morton House</wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationAddressOne>
<wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationAddressTwo>Morton Road</wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationAddressTwo>
<wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationCity>Darlington</wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationCity>
<wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationPostCode>DL1 4PT</wd:PrimaryJobPostingLocationPostCode>
<wd:AdditionalLocations>Rotherham - Thames Street</wd:AdditionalLocations> -- Ignore this, it is to make the grouping work on the report
<wd:ScheduledWeeklyHours>40</wd:ScheduledWeeklyHours>
<wd:Company>Mears Limited</wd:Company>
<wd:CostCenter>288 AASC - North East, Yorks, &amp; Humber</wd:CostCenter>
<wd:JobRequisitionID>REQ0011510</wd:JobRequisitionID>  -- This is the unique identifier for a job requisition
<wd:JobPostingTitle>Head of Region</wd:JobPostingTitle>
<wd:AdvertText>Annual salary: up to £60,000.00<p style="text-align:inherit"/>
<p style="text-align:inherit"/>
<p/>
<p>Mears Housing Management is a successful business within Mears Group PLC, having grown in 5 years to a nationally based management business with 12,000 homes and contracts with 50 Local Authorities and Central Government.  We house many people in housing need who would otherwise be living in costly and inappropriate accommodation and as such we have a strong social pursue in everything we do. Our red thread runs through everything we do and we want people who share our values to help us continue to deliver customer focused services and innovatively push the boundaries of the sector. We empower our people to lead by example, taking ownership and responsibility to work to the best of their abilities and effectively collaborate with colleagues and partners to exceed the expectations of both clients and customers.  <br />
</p>
<p>With ambitious plans to continue this rapid growth, we are looking for a Head of Region in the North East, Yorkshire and Humber Region. This is a great opportunity within our Housing Management business, following the success of the Asylum Accommodation and Support Contract win.   This role plays a pivotal role in supporting the delivery of our commercial targets and ambitions so we are looking for an experienced leader who shares our values but can also deliver service excellence alongside challenging contractual requirements. </p>
<p/>
<p>
<span>Reporting to the Contract Delivery Director, you will be responsible for the overall commercial and operational delivery within the contract region of the service users and client. Your strong leadership skills and strategic vision will be key to the success of this contract, embedding an output driven and customer focused culture within your team supported by robust processes, strong relationships with key stakeholders and accurate record keeping to evidence performance to the client. Your team will keep the service user at the heart of the service and ensure safeguarding is at the heart of your team’s work. You will effectively manage your team to embed these key priorities into their day to day responsibilities and work collaboratively with the Service Delivery Centre to ensure its success through -</span>
</p>
<p/>
<ul>
<li>Responsibility for the contract delivery ensuring full compliance and meeting of  obligations within an assigned region.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Delivery of evidenced successful outcomes for Key Performance Indicators along with internal &amp; commercial targets.</li>
<li>Lead, manage, motivate and support staff to deliver contractual service.</li>
<li>Create a positive, continuous improvement culture within the business; embedding and manging through the principals of reward &amp; recognition and ownership &amp; accountability.   </li>
<li>Delivery of service to ensure safeguarding and welfare are fully considered and embedded in processes.</li>
<li>Ensure effective management of risks through planning and service delivery; including escalating to senior management for action in a timely manner. </li>
<li>Development and growth of relationships with internal colleagues, third parties and external organisations to support service delivery and property procurement. </li>
<li>Overall responsibility for the delivery of a customer focused service to our service users ensuring a tailored approach to meet individual needs whilst being culturally aware and sensitive of circumstances</li>
<li>Work collaboratively and proactively with the central service delivery centre to ensure client, customer and service users receive an exceptional service. </li>
<li>Delivery of performance and service reporting as requested by service delivery centre, line manager and other senior management, ensuring escalation of all risks and concerns</li>
<li>Overall responsibility to ensure all records and IT data on systems is accurate and meets contractual requirements.</li>
<li>Undertake ad-hoc projects and provide support and cover for colleagues and teams within Mears Housing Management </li>
<li>Ensure full compliance with Mears code of conduct, contractual terms and group policies &amp; procedures</li>
</ul>
<p/>
<p>At Mears, we recognise that our people are our greatest asset and as such we believe this is an exciting opportunity for an exceptional operational and strategic professional to make a real difference to customers, communities and the people they lead.</p>
<p/>
<p>
<b>
<u>What are we looking for?</u>
</b>
</p>
<p/>
<ul>
<li>Demonstrable experience of working in a similar operational</li>
<li>Management of the delivery of front line customer service teams.</li>
<li>Experience/knowledge of social housing, property or public sector would be hugely advantageous although not essential.</li>
<li>Strong people management skills with an ability to manage managers and motivate, and lead teams</li>
<li>Stakeholder management skills in order to effectively work across all functions</li>
<li>Ability to establish and manage relationships with internal and external customers/clients</li>
<li>Commercially driven, results focused and output driven to deliver contractual requirements</li>
<li>Commitment to put the customer at the heart of the service to deliver a great user experience to a diverse client group </li>
<li>Process driven candidates with great attention to detail and meticulous record keeping evidenced by maintaining accurate information on IT systems</li>
<li>Continuous service improvement - this is a new contract and we need to be open to sharing best practice to ensure we have the right processes and resources in place </li>
<li>Performance culture and collaborative working in order to effectively manage and escalate risk</li>
</ul>
<p/>
<p>If you are interested, then we want to hear from you.  Simply make your first click and join us on our journey..</p>
<p/>
</wd:AdvertText>
<wd:TimeType>Full time</wd:TimeType>
<wd:locations_group> --  These are the additional locations, this listing can include any number and will include/duplicate the primary job posting location
<wd:AdditionalLocationsID>L000073</wd:AdditionalLocationsID>
<wd:AdditionalLocationName>Rotherham - Thames Street</wd:AdditionalLocationName>
<wd:AdditionalLocationHierarchy>Yorkshire &amp; Humber</wd:AdditionalLocationHierarchy>  -- This is what we use to classify the locations into regions
<wd:AdditionalLocationAddressOne>Thames Street</wd:AdditionalLocationAddressOne>
<wd:AdditionalLocationAddressCity>Rotherham</wd:AdditionalLocationAddressCity>
<wd:AdditionalLocationAddressPostalCode>S60 1LU</wd:AdditionalLocationAddressPostalCode>
</wd:locations_group>
<wd:locations_group>
<wd:AdditionalLocationsID>LOCATION-3-642</wd:AdditionalLocationsID>
<wd:AdditionalLocationName>Darlington</wd:AdditionalLocationName>
<wd:AdditionalLocationHierarchy>Yorkshire &amp; Humber</wd:AdditionalLocationHierarchy>  -- This is what we use to classify the locations into regions
<wd:AdditionalLocationAddressOne>Morton House</wd:AdditionalLocationAddressOne>
<wd:AdditionalLocationAddressTwo>Morton Road</wd:AdditionalLocationAddressTwo>
<wd:AdditionalLocationAddressCity>Darlington</wd:AdditionalLocationAddressCity>
<wd:AdditionalLocationAddressPostalCode>DL1 4PT</wd:AdditionalLocationAddressPostalCode>
</wd:locations_group>
<wd:ExternalApplyURL>https://mearsgroup.wd3.myworkdayjobs.com/External_Career_Site/job/Darlington/Regional-Head-of-Operations_REQ0011510-1/apply</wd:ExternalApplyURL> --  URL link to apply for the job, this is the live system, so please don't test apply to a job.
</wd:Report_Entry>
